Finding Aid for the Sass Nielson papers 1974-1976 LSC.2162
UCLA Library Special Collections
Sass Nielsen papers
1974-1976
LSC.2162
UCLA Library Special Collections
0.4 linear feet (1 box)
Sass Nielsen worked at Disney Studios in Burbank, California throughout the 1990s. Her advocacy work, growing out of the group Hollywood Supports (a nonprofit organization promoting awareness of AIDS and gay issues) concerned the extension of health benefits for same sex partners as well as organizing around lesbian and gay issues in the workplace. In 1992, she successfully organized to form the Lesbian and Gay United Employees (LEAGUE). This collection includes research, correspondence, and collected materials related to gay and lesbian issues including information from activist organizations as well as publications treating the issue historically.
Nielsen, Sass
Conditions Governing Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sandra (Sass) P. Nielsen, 2013.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library.
Sponsor
The June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA is an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW), and the UCLA Library. These collections expand the pool of primary source materials available to researchers and to the community at large. This partnership was initiated by CSW and is funded by the National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) to inventory, organize, preserve, and digitize more than eighty Mazer collections pertaining to lesbian and feminist activism and writings.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7384778
Biography
Sass Nielsen worked at Disney Studios in Burbank, California throughout the 1990s. Her advocacy work, growing out of the group Hollywood Supports (a nonprofit organization promoting awareness of AIDS and gay issues) concerned the extension of health benefits for same sex partners as well as organizing around lesbian and gay issues in the workplace. In 1992, she successfully organized to form the Lesbian and Gay United Employees (LEAGUE). As a young woman she was kicked out of the armed forces for being a lesbian. She also wrote fiction.
Scope and Content
This collection includes research, correspondence, and collected materials related to gay and lesbian issues including information from activist organizations as well as publications treating the issue historically.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials arranged by type.
June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives.; Nielsen, Sass -- Archives.; Gay rights--United States.; Lesbian activists--United States--Archives.
- Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Content
  Brochures, flyers and letters from the Lambda Legal Defense Fund.
- Newsletters and newspaper clippings, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Clippings and publications including It's Time: Monthly Newsletter of the National Gay Task Force and Gayzette: The Weekly Philadelphia Gayzette.
- The Gay Academic Union, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Conference schedules, biographies and abstracts of participants of the 1974 Gay Academic Union Conference.
- Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Collected letters from individuals and organizations concerning various issues related to gay and lesbian feminist activism.
- Flyers, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Collected writings, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Feminist and activist works published by other authors and collected by Sass Nielsen.
- Consciousness raising materials, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  How-to guides, samples of consciousness raising techniques.
- YWCA materials, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Information about women's programming including conferences, series and activities.
- Assorted materials, circa 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Resources, circa 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Resources including catalogs, contact information, brochures and pamphlets about available resources and group opportunities from gay and lesbian activist organizations.
- Surveys, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Surveys about sexual experience and relationships.